RG 004:047, East Windsor Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
East Windsor Probate Court records
1782-1976
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (East Windsor District)
84.5 cubic feet
Record books, 1782-1923; Probate files, 1782-1976.
RG004_047
1927-021, 2011-011, 2011-014
Historical Note
East Windsor, Hartford County, Town established in May 1768, Parent Town: Windsor
The East Windsor Probate District was constituted May 1782, from the Hartford and Stafford Probate Districts. At one time it also served the towns of Bolton, May 1782 - May 1789; East Hartford, May 1783 - May 1797; Ellington, May 1786 - May 1826; Enfield, May 1782 - May 30, 1831; Glastonbury, May 1782 - May 1797; and South Windsor, May 1845 - January 4, 2011. The East Windsor Probate District merged with the Windsor Probate District on January 5, 2011 to create the Region #4 Probate District which serves the municipalities of East Windsor, South Windsor, and Windsor.
Town of East Windsor, Probate District chronology:
May 1768 - May 1782, Hartford District
May 1768 - May 1782, Stafford District (covering Ellington Parish of East Windsor)
May 1768 - May 1786, Stafford District (covering the eastern part of Ellington Parish)
May 1782 - January 4, 2011, East Windsor District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Region #4 District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes 1-25, 1782-1923. Contact the probate court to access record books after Volume 25.
Probate files, 1782-1976. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. Includes a small number of files from the New Haven Probate District that pre-date the creation of the Bethany Probate District in 1854. Most of these files are for incompetency cases.
Inventory control book, 1782-1899 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered consecutively from 1 to 25.
Probate files are arranged by accession. Accession 1927-021 is arranged alphabetically. Accession 2011-011 is arranged in two alphabetical series, the first containing decedent estates only and the second containing all matters including decedent estates.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in accession 1927-021 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2011-011.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut - Bolton; Probate records -- Connecticut - East Hartford; Probate records -- Connecticut - East Windsor; Probate records -- Connecticut - Ellington; Probate records -- Connecticut - Enfield; Probate records -- Connecticut - Glastonbury; Probate records -- Connecticut - South Windsor Windsor
Places:
Bolton (Conn.); East Hartford (Conn.); East Windsor (Conn.); Ellington (Conn.); Enfield (Conn.); Glastonbury (Conn.); South Windsor (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1976 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
Accession 2011-014, Record books, 1782-1923; and Accession 2011-011, Probate files, 1900-1976, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, Volumes 1-11, 13-14, 16-19, 21-23, 1782-1922; probate files 1782-1915 (Accession 1927-021 only); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1927-021 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): September 20, 1927 (1782-1899); October 14, 1927 (1782-1899). They were interfiled intoone alphabetic sequence.
The probate files in accession 2011-011 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on August 6, 2010 and August 25, 2010.
The record books in accession 2011-014 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on August 25, 2010.
Container List
- Record books, 1782-1923; 13.5 cubic feet (25 volumes); 2011-014
  - Records, 1782-1791 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1791-1812 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1805-1813 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1813-1821 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1817-1826 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1825-1837 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1837-1847 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1838-1855 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1855-1865 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1861-1870 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1870-1877 (Volume 11)
  - Orders and decrees, 1873-1881 (Volume 12)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1877-1890 (Volume 13)
  - Orders and decrees, 1881-1890 (Volume 14)
  - Bonds, 1881-1913 (Volume 15)
  - Orders and decrees, 1890-1896 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1889-1907 (Volume 17)
  - Orders and decrees, 1896-1905 (Volume 18)
  - Records, 1907-1913 (Volume 19)
  - Bonds, 1903-1923 (Volume 20)
  - Orders and decrees, 1905-1912 (Volume 21)
  - Records, 1911-1917 (Volume 22)
  - Orders and decrees, 1912-1918 (Volume 23)
  - Records, 1917-1923 (Volume 24)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Orders and decrees, 1918-1923 (Volume 25)
- Probate files, 1782-1899; 9 cubic feet; 1927-021
  - Abbe - Bancroft, T. (Drawer 1)
  - Bancroft, U. - Brown, J. (Drawer 2)
  - Brown, K. - Driscoll (Drawer 3)
  - Ducit - Green, J. (Drawer 4)
  - Green, K. - Lee (Drawer 5)
  - Leonard - Orcutt (Drawer 6)
  - Osborn - Robinson (Drawer 7)
  - Robertson - Talcott, F. (Drawer 8)
  - Talcott, G. - Zohn; Miscellaneous (Drawer 9)
- Inventory Control Book, 1782-1899; T003073
  Index of the two accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1927-021
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate files, 1900-1976; 62 cubic feet; 2011-011
  - Decedent estates
    - Abbe - Barber, Mary Foster (Box 1)
    - Barber, Josephine K. - Bluzic (Box 2)
    - Boies - Burke (Box 3)
    - Burnham - Charlton (Box 4)
    - Chase - Crockett (Box 5)
    - Cummings - Dowd (Box 6)
    - Drake - Farrow (Box 7)
    - Felt - Geissler, Rose (Box 8)
    - Geissler, Rudolph C. - Griffin (Box 9)
    - Grimason - Hensel (Box 10)
    - Herbert - Jenkins (Box 11)
    - Jennings - Kilman (Box 12)
    - King - Lane, A. (Box 13)
    - Lane, H. - Malasky (Box 14)
    - Malinou - Meade (Box 15)
    - Mederos - Newberry, J. (Box 16)
    - Newberry, L. - Pasqualini (Box 17)
    - Patria - Potter (Box 18)
    - Potwin - Roe, E. (Box 19)
    - Roe, V. - Shepard, A. (Box 20)
    - Shepard, J. - Smith (Box 21)
    - Snow - Taylor (Box 22)
    - Tefft - Wadsworth, A. (Box 23)
    - Wadsworth, F. - Wojcak (Box 24)
    - Wojna - Zokites (Box 25)
  - All matters
    Includes decedent estates
    - Abbe - Anderson (Box 25)
    - Andresen - Bancroft, Elizabeth (Box 26)
    - Bancroft, Ellen - Belknap (Box 27)
    - Bellemare - Bouchard (Box 28)
    - Boucher - Burkhart (Box 29)
    - Burnette - Chagnon (Box 30)
    - Chamberlain - Coope (Box 31)
    - Copage - Davids (Box 32)
    - Davidson - Dominick (Box 33)
    - Donihee - Elliott (Box 34)
    - Ellis - Fessoveist (Box 35)
    - Fetko - Gallagher (Box 36)
    - Gallo - Grant, E. (Box 37)
    - Grant, F. - Hanan (Box 38)
    - Handy - Hills (Box 39)
    - Hilt - Jennings (Box 40)
    - Jesseman - Kawa (Box 41)
    - Kayross - Kountes (Box 42)
    - Kovera - Lathrop, C. (Box 43)
    - Lathrop, H. - Luts (Box 44)
    - Lutwinas - Mastrangelo (Box 45)
    - Mastrio - McLoughlin (Box 46)
    - McNally - Mohn (Box 47)
    - Molloy - Nash (Box 48)
    - Nasuta - Nutter (Box 49)
    - Nutting - Pastula, J. (Box 50)
    - Pastula, T. - Pollak (Box 51)
    - Pollard - Rawson (Box 52)
    - Raymond - Roller (Box 53)
    - Rolocut - Schlicting (Box 54)
    - Schlude - Simler (Box 55)
    - Simmons - Spokes (Box 56)
    - Squires - Sunega (Box 57)
    - Surber - Tomashunas (Box 58)
    - Tomel - Waicunas (Box 59)
    - Waikznis - Widak (Box 60)
    - Wilcox - Zeleski (Box 61)
    - Zemaitis - Zysk (Box 62)